<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Robert on Nexten - Cybersecurity, Application Security, Embedded Security</title>
    <link>https://nexten.ie/authors/david-robert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in David Robert on Nexten - Cybersecurity, Application Security, Embedded Security</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 11:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nexten.ie/authors/david-robert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ESP32, Secure Boot (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://nexten.ie/blog/2023/11/26/esp32-secureboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 11:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nexten.ie/blog/2023/11/26/esp32-secureboot/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Secure Boot ESP32 series (Part 1) This article is part of a series on the Security Features of the Espressif ESP32 microcontroller series. This includes MCUs based on the Xtensa Instruction Set (e.g. ESP32, ESP32-S3), as well as MCUs based on the RISC-V Instruction Set (e.g. ESP32-C3). This is the first article of the series, which will cover:
Secure Boot V1 (AES Based Secure Boot) (this article) Secure Boot V2 (RSA Based Secure Boot) Flash encryption (AES-XTS and legacy) AES, SHA, RSA, DS and HMAC accelerators World Controller to allow isolated execution environments Introduction ESP32 SoCs are very popular System On a Chip (SoC) microcontrollers made by the company Espressif.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio IoT</title>
      <link>https://nexten.ie/blog/2023/04/11/audio-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 11:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nexten.ie/blog/2023/04/11/audio-iot/</guid>
      <description>Audio-net: an IoT audio device based on ESP32 SoC This is a prototype of an internet and Bluetooth connected music device.
The hardware used supports, and has been tested to do the following:
Audio inputs can be looped over, recorded to SD card, uploaded to the cloud. Audio input can be a codec input or a Bluetooth A2DP source. Mixing of multiple sound inputs. Wi-Fi connection to stream audio (to the cloud, or from the cloud).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
